



Victor Picaud Graduate Analyst

victor.picaud@cognizant.com



+4179 964 31 16

Summary

I am a passionate data engineer with experience working on innovative ML solutions. about data engineering and analytics and have worked for multiple large organizations where I successfully delivered mission critical solutions, in the field of predictive maintenance - heavy industry, recruitment optimization - shared service centers, safety analytics, for instance.

Areas of expertise

Technical Skills:

 C, C++, Python, Python NLP & Object recognition (opency, tensorflow, spaCy, ray Rlib), DBT full courses (certification), Informatica Power Center, HTML, Javascript, Three.js, React JS, React Native, Angular JS, Windows, Unix/Linux, OSX, Certified GCP Professional ML Engineer.

Industries

- Life Sciences
- Safety Analytics
- Manufacturing

Work experience



Cognizant Started Feb 2022 - Present

birlasoft

Birlasoft Solutions May 2021 – November 2021



Sep 2020 – March 2021

Graduate Analyst at Cognizant

Completed multiple training sessions on Informatica Power Center, DBT and Snowflake for DWH an ETL/ELT.

Passed the GCP Professional ML Engineer Certification

Data Science Intern (graduation internship - 6 months) - Paris

- I worked on three Machine Learning algorithms for clients, targeting Natural Language Processing for various use cases as well as a PoC (Proof of Concept) of a react web app with the capabilities of predicting employee attrition.
- I participated in the PoC for Safety Analytics in a record time of 4 weeks for Hyundai, in charge of the Data Science side of the project.

IT Intern, Switzerland

- Development of TIS mobile (an app that gives employees access to live plant data worldwide for a target of 10 000 user approx) in React Native. The targeted business case was to optimise the workload of all the technicians in the group in order to allow further innovations and to gain operational efficiencies notably in maintenance.
- Implementation of a PoC of a deep learning image recognition software for rock size detection that helps prevent blockages in cement mills.

2015 - 2016

Education

Epitech Paris, Graduate in Computer Science 2017- 2021

Wuhan University, China, Master in Software Engineering 2019 - 2020

Language

French English



Lycée Pierre Gilles De Gennes, Scientific Preparatory Classes - Mathematics &Physics . 2016 - 2017 Lycée Buffon, Scientific Preparatory Classes MPSI.